<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Raphael Borges</title>
    <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Raphael Borges</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt-br</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.r11s.com.br/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Octopilot</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/octopilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/octopilot/</guid>
      <description>In 2020, while building Dailymotion&amp;rsquo;s new Continuous Delivery platform, I found myself needing a tool to automate the creation of pull requests to implement our Gitops-based workflow. No existing tool really matches our needs, so I created Octopilot: a CLI tool designed to help you automate your Gitops workflow, by automatically creating and merging GitHub Pull Requests to update specific content in Git repositories.
You can read more about Octopilot in a blog post I wrote on Medium: Introducing Octopilot: a CLI to automate the creation of GitHub pull requests in your gitops workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins X Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/jenkins-x-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/jenkins-x-projects/</guid>
      <description>I started using Jenkins X in 2018, and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to the project.
Since 2020, I started contributing more to Jenkins X by creating new components, mainly for observability - but also web UIs.
JX Pipelines Visualizer The first new project I created for Jenkins X was the JX Pipelines Visualizer: a web UI to visualize the pipelines and their logs.
New @jenkinsxio UI to visualize your pipelines and logs: https://t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various OpenShift-related projects</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/openshift-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/openshift-projects/</guid>
      <description>In 2015-2016, while using OpenShift, I developed a few small open-source projects on top of the Kubernetes/OpenShift APIs:
 OpenShift Dashboard OpenShift Cucumber OpenShift GitHub Hooks OpenShift/Git Integration OpenShift Flowdock Notifier  OpenShift Dashboard When I started using OpenShift, I quickly realized that it was missing a global view of the cluster state. In August 2015 I developed a Web Dashboard for visualization of multi-projects resources in OpenShift.
This gave me the opportunity to learn the OpenShift/Kubernetes API early on, and improve my Go skills - by reading the OpenShift and Kubernetes code bases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins Rundeck Plugin</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/jenkins-rundeck-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/jenkins-rundeck-plugin/</guid>
      <description>In 2011, I wrote a Jenkins plugin to integrate Rundeck as a &amp;ldquo;publisher&amp;rdquo;: the Rundeck plugin.
This plugin allows the creation of continuous delivery pipelines, using Jenkins to build your software and Rundeck to deploy it. I talked about it at the Paris DevOps meetup in march 2011: Continuous Deployment with Jenkins and Rundeck.
Note that this plugin is now maintained by the Rundeck team, and is still used by many people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rundeck API Java Client</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/rundeck-api-java-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/rundeck-api-java-client/</guid>
      <description>In 2011, following the Jenkins Rundeck plugin, I extracted the code that talked to the Rundeck REST API into its own project: the Rundeck API Java Client.
The goal was to be able to write more software in Java using Rundeck&amp;rsquo;s REST API, for example the Rundeck Remote CLI, or writing scripts
Note that this project is now maintained by the Rundeck team at rundeck/rundeck-api-java-client, and is still used by many projects/people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flowdock to Elasticsearch</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/flowdock2es/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/flowdock2es/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, I wanted to play with Elasticsearch and Kibana, so I created a small project to import data from a Flowdock instance into Elasticsearch, and then build a Kibana dashboard to visualize the Flowdock usage.
It is written in Scala and uses the Flowdock REST API to retrieve data, and the Elastic4s scala lib to populate the Elasticsearch index. I also contributed to the Elastic4s open-source project.
Here is a screenshot of the Kibana dashboard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paris DevOps</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/parisdevops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/parisdevops/</guid>
      <description>In 2011, soon after the creation of the Paris DevOps Meetup group, I joined the team and help organize the meetups.
I built the parisdevops.fr using Jekyll on GitHub Pages: https://github.com/parisdevops/parisdevops.github.com
I wrote content on the website and organized meetups for a few months in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>