<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raphael Borges</title>
    <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Raphael Borges</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt-br</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.r11s.com.br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A custom action to deploy mdBook #githubhack2023</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-05-article-action-mdbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-05-article-action-mdbook/</guid>
      <description>I developed this GitHub Action to automate the deployment of ebooks using customized configurations that better suit the needs of the projects I am involved in. The motivation behind creating this action was to streamline the process and eliminate manual steps required for ebook deployment. It participated in the GitHub + DEV 2023 Hackathon.
You can read the full blog post - in english on dev.to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mdBookCLI</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/mdbookcli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/creations/mdbookcli/</guid>
      <description>While working on the implementation of the &amp;ldquo;Demystifying Prometheus&amp;rdquo; book from LINUXtips, I noticed the need to simplify the process and address certain limitations in the default mdBook interface.
The mdBookCLI introduces multilingual support in a manner distinct from the standard mdBook, generating a homepage that allows users to choose their preferred language. Additionally, it includes extra customizations not available in the default mdBook version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/demystifying-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/demystifying-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>The book Demystifying Prometheus is a crucial component of the Demystifying Prometheus training offered by LINUXtips.
I contributed to the development of the ebook version, implementing new features and making corrections to links, texts, and titles.
See all my contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>py2rs</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/py2rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/py2rs/</guid>
      <description>py2rs is a quick reference guide for the Pythonista in process of becoming a Rustacean.
In a conversation with Bruno Rocha, I discovered his need to implement an ebook in a project of his that facilitates the migration of Python developers to the Rust language. Since I had already developed the mdbookcli tool, I implemented this tool to generate the book.
See all my contributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Fast, Secure, and Scalable Recursive DNS Server (pt-br)</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-03-article-ubound-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-03-article-ubound-dns/</guid>
      <description>In March 2023, I wrote a blog post on dev.to titled &amp;ldquo;Um servidor DNS Recursivo rápido, seguro e escalável (A Fast, Secure, and Scalable Recursive DNS Server).&amp;rdquo; The post talks about Unbound, Recursive DNS, and best practices in security, while also providing guidance on creating your own DNS.
 It received more than 1k views across all platforms, It was re-published on Linkedin,  You can read the full blog post on dev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digestabot</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/digestabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/digestabot/</guid>
      <description>I contributed by suggesting a correction in the documentation where the wrong version reference was used. Additionally, I pointed out a typographical error in the code that prevented the &amp;lsquo;create_pr_update&amp;rsquo; variable from changing its value to &amp;lsquo;true,&amp;rsquo; causing the bot to fail in opening the pull request for image updates. The correction pull request was created by the project maintainer, Carlos Panato, after we discussed the issue on Twitter.
After using it a few times, I missed the option to customize the pull request message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you heard about Digestabot? (pt-br)</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-12-article-digestabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/publications/2023-12-article-digestabot/</guid>
      <description>I composed this blog post shortly after the release of Digestabot, a new tool from Chainguard, to discuss how to use and the purpose of each feature. Providing detailed instructions on implementing this GitHub Action in your repository.
You can read the full blog post in portuguese on dev.to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://www.r11s.com.br/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.r11s.com.br/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>