<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mdBook on Raphael Borges</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/tags/mdbook/</link><description>Recent content in mdBook on Raphael Borges</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>pt-br</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://r11s.com.br/tags/mdbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demystifying Prometheus</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/demystifying-prometheus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/demystifying-prometheus/</guid><description>The book Demystifying Prometheus is a crucial component of the Demystifying Prometheus training offered by LINUXtips.
I contributed to the development of the ebook version, implementing new features and making corrections to links, texts, and titles.
See all my contributions.</description></item><item><title>py2rs</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/py2rs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/py2rs/</guid><description>py2rs is a quick reference guide for the Pythonista in process of becoming a Rustacean.
In a conversation with Bruno Rocha, I discovered his need to implement an ebook in a project of his that facilitates the migration of Python developers to the Rust language. Since I had already developed the mdbookcli tool, I implemented this tool to generate the book.
See all my contributions.</description></item><item><title>mdBookCLI</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/projects/creations/mdbookcli/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/projects/creations/mdbookcli/</guid><description>While working on the implementation of the &amp;ldquo;Demystifying Prometheus&amp;rdquo; book from LINUXtips, I noticed the need to simplify the process and address certain limitations in the default mdBook interface.
The mdBookCLI introduces multilingual support in a manner distinct from the standard mdBook, generating a homepage that allows users to choose their preferred language. Additionally, it includes extra customizations not available in the default mdBook version.</description></item></channel></rss>