<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub Actions on Raphael Borges</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/tags/github-actions/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub Actions on Raphael Borges</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>pt-br</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://r11s.com.br/tags/github-actions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A custom action to deploy mdBook #githubhack2023</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/publications/2023-05-article-action-mdbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/publications/2023-05-article-action-mdbook/</guid><description>I developed this GitHub Action to automate the deployment of ebooks using customized configurations that better suit the needs of the projects I am involved in. The motivation behind creating this action was to streamline the process and eliminate manual steps required for ebook deployment. It participated in the GitHub + DEV 2023 Hackathon.
You can read the full blog post - in english on dev.to.</description></item><item><title>Digestabot</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/digestabot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/projects/contributions/digestabot/</guid><description>I contributed by suggesting a correction in the documentation where the wrong version reference was used. Additionally, I pointed out a typographical error in the code that prevented the &amp;lsquo;create_pr_update&amp;rsquo; variable from changing its value to &amp;lsquo;true,&amp;rsquo; causing the bot to fail in opening the pull request for image updates. The correction pull request was created by the project maintainer, Carlos Panato, after we discussed the issue on Twitter.
After using it a few times, I missed the option to customize the pull request message.</description></item><item><title>Have you heard about Digestabot? (pt-br)</title><link>https://r11s.com.br/publications/2023-12-article-digestabot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://r11s.com.br/publications/2023-12-article-digestabot/</guid><description>I composed this blog post shortly after the release of Digestabot, a new tool from Chainguard, to discuss how to use and the purpose of each feature. Providing detailed instructions on implementing this GitHub Action in your repository.
You can read the full blog post in portuguese on dev.to.</description></item></channel></rss>